The secret lives of animals revealed!
Barnyard is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Steve Oedekerk.
Otis is a mischievous, carefree Holstein cow who lives on a farm where,
unbeknownst to humans, the animals are anthropomorphic.
He prefers having fun with his best friends: Pip the mouse, Freddy the ferret, Peck the rooster,
and Pig the pig - rather than following strict rules and accepting responsibility.
This annoys his stern adoptive father Ben, the leader of the farm's community.
One evening, Otis convinces Ben to cover his night watch so he can attend a massive party in the barn and impress
Daisy, a pregnant cow who recently arrived at the farm with her best friend Bessy as a newcomer.
As the animals party, Dag the coyote and his pack
attempt to raid the chicken coop.
Ben fends them off alone but is fatally wounded and killed.
Otis must now learn the value of responsibility when he
becomes the leader of his farm home's community.
Otis (voice), played by Kevin James.
Daisy (voice), played by Courteney Cox.
Ben (voice), played by Sam Elliott.
Miles (voice), played by Danny Glover.
Bessy (voice), played by Wanda Sykes.
Etta (voice), played by Andie MacDowell.
Barnyard (also known as Barnyard: The Original Party Animals) is a 2006
American animated comedy film written and directed by Steve Oedekerk.
The film features an ensemble cast, including Kevin James, Courteney Cox, Sam
Elliott, Danny Glover, Wanda Sykes, Andie MacDowell and David Koechner.
It tells the story of Otis, a carefree Holstein cow, who learns the value of responsibility when he becomes
the leader of his farm home's community after his adoptive father's death from a coyote attack.
Barnyard was released in the United States on
August 4, 2006, by Paramount Pictures.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $116.5
million worldwide against a $51 million production budget.
A sequel television series, Back at the Barnyard, premiered in 2007.
The film explores themes of farm, peasant, villain, family, farmer.
The tone is lighthearted.